Hi everyone, I'm Patrick and in this video I show you how I would learn
machine learning if I could start over. For context, I'm a machine learning developer
advocate at AssemblyAI and before that I worked several years as
software developer and ML engineer and I also teach Python and machine
learning on my own YouTube channel. So I would say I'm pretty experienced
in the field, but I know that the available courses out there
can be overwhelming for beginners, so I hope to give you some guidance
with this video. The demand for machine learning engineers is still increasing
every year, so it's a great skill to have. I divided this learning path into
seven steps that should take you about three months to finish. Of course,
this can vary depending on how much time and effort you want to put into
this, and I know that everyone learns differently or might have different goals.
So this is just my personal take on how to learn machine
learning. You can use this guide if you just want to explore machine learning as
a hobby, but also if you plan to find a job in the field,
I will mention a few more tips about the job search in the end.
So lets jump into the study plan. The first thing I recommend is to lay
the foundation with some math basics. Now you might say
math is not really necessary anymore and this is partly true.
The available machine learning frameworks abstract the math away
and I know many machine learning engineers so dont need it in their day job
at all. However, in my opinion, knowing the underlying math
provides you with a better foundation and better understanding of how the algorithms
work and it makes your life easier when you run into problems.
Also, I think there is beauty in the underlying math
that makes the machines learn. So for me, knowing the math
sparked my excitement even more. Now you dont need to get too deep into
this. A great website with free resources is Khan Academy.
So my recommendation is just to take some basic courses and
then move on. And then later when you do the actual machine learning course
and dont understand everything, then come back here and learn the missing
topics. Oh and by the way, you find all the resources and recommended courses
in the description below. The next step is to learn Python. It is
the number one programming language for machine learning and there is
no way around it. All major machine learning frameworks are built
with it and all major courses use Python for their exercises.
So having decent Python skills is essential to build machine
learning projects. Now you don't need to become an advanced software
developer, but a little bit more than the beginner level would be great.
One great thing about Python is that it is very beginner friendly,
and in my opinion it's the best first programming language you can
learn. I recommend two free courses on YouTube, one four
hour beginner course and one six hour intermediate course,
and then you should have a solid base. This step is what I call the
machine learning tech stack and consists of the most important python libraries
for machine learning, data science, and data visualization. This step
is a bit optional because you can also pick up these skills later when you
do the actual machine learning course, but I think it's great to build
the foundation first and then it will be easier later. The three libraries
I recommend at this point are numpy, which is the base for
everything pandas, which is important for data handling,
and matplotlib, which is needed for visualization. These libraries
are used in almost every machine learning project. That's why I would include
them in your learning path at this point. Again, you don't need
to learn too much here. I recommend just following one
free crash course for each library and then later pick
up more advanced concepts if you need them. At this point you dont have
to learn the machine learning courses like scikit learn, Tensorflow, or Pytorch.
You could of course if you want, but these are included in the machine
learning course I show you in a moment, so you can pick these up
later. Now that weve covered the coding skills, it is finally time
for the actual machine learning course. There are many great ones available,
but the most popular, and in my opinion also one of the best
ones, is the machine learning specialization by Andrew Ng on
Coursera. This specialization includes its three courses.
It got revamped just a few months ago and now includes Python
with Numpy, scikit learn and Tensorflow for the code.
So you not only learn all the essential machine learning concepts,
but also get your first hands on experience with the ML
libraries. It is extensive and it takes several weeks to finish,
but it's worth it after these courses. I have one more recommendation for
you. I suggest to implement a few algorithms from scratch
in Python using only pure Python and numpy,
for example by following my ML from scratch playlist here on YouTube.
This is completely optional, but it helped me to properly understand
some of the concepts from Andrew's course, and a lot of students have told
me the same feedback, so check it out if you want to. Also, we plan
to release an updated version of the ML from scratch course here
on the AssemblyAI channel, so make sure to subscribe to
our channel and don't miss it. Now I recommend getting even more hands on
and learning more about data preparation. For this kaggle has
awesome free courses on their website. I recommend at
least the intro to ML and intermediate ML courses.
They are lightweight compared to the previous one and some material is
just a refresher for you, but youll learn more about data preprocessing
and data preparation with pandas. Each lesson has a theory
part and then some coding exercises. It also gives you a
gentle introduction to the Kaggle platform and you learn how to make
code submissions on Kaggle which is perfect for the next point.
Now its time to practice as much as possible and
apply your knowledge to real world machine learning problems.
For this the best platform is kaggle.com.
it provides thousands of different datasets and challenges where you
can participate. Participating in challenges can motivate
you a lot. Now I wouldnt try making it to the top or even winning
prize money with this because to be honest, this requires true expertise
and also a lot of GPU power. But I would still try
to tweak your solutions multiple times by learning
more about data preprocessing and also about hyperparameter tuning.
You can then use Kaggle competitions to build your portfolio and put
them on your cv. So in my opinion, Kaggle is an awesome
platform and you should practice here as much as possible. Of course, you can also
tackle other machine learning problems outside of Kaggle. It just makes your
life a little bit easier because it provides you with the datasets, a platform
to evaluate the projects, and there is a whole community around it.
At this point you can already be super proud of yourself.
And now in this last section, I want to give you a few more tips.
If your goal is to get a job, the tasks of ML engineers vary
a lot and it's not possible to know everything. For example,
some positions are specialized in computer vision or NLP,
or they require you to have experience with a specific ML framework
or even mlops requirements like how to deploy and scale scale
ML apps. MLops is a whole field on its own, so I may cover this
in a separate video. My point is, you have to decide in which field you
want to work and then look at the requirements in some corresponding job descriptions
and then specialize in this direction. Another great tip I can
give you, and this is something I wish I had done earlier in my career,
is to start a blog. You can write tutorials, share what you've learned,
which projects you have built, which problems you have faced along the way,
and how you've solved them. By writing about a topic, you can deepen your
knowledge and then you can use this as a resource on your cv.
Trust me, this will increase your chances to get an interview a lot.
Alright, that's my recommendation for a machine learning study guide.
Again, this might not be suited for everyone. This is just how
I would learn machine learning if I had to start over. Just one more
quick addition. If you prefer learning with books, then you can check out these
two books. Let me know in the comments if this was helpful,
or if you have any other suggestions you would add to the plan.
Don't forget to check out the resource list I put in the description below and
then I hope to see you in the next video.